(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
不知火フレア 3rd Anniversary Live SKYSONAR
Flare Shiranui 3rd Anniversary Live SKYSONAR
Yeah!!
全力ジャンピング！
作詞・作曲 篠崎あやと/橘亮祐
Zenryoku Jumping!
Lyrics & Composition: Ayato Shinozaki / Ryosuke Tachibana
どこへ行こうか
Where shall we go?
計画なしで
Without a plan,
歌いながら気の向く方へ
Singing as we go wherever our hearts desire
迷ってるの？
Are you lost?
冒険してるの？
Are you adventuring?
それはみんな次第！
That's all up to you!
まだまだ楽しみ足りない
Still haven't had enough fun yet
でもでも時間が足りない
But, but there's not enough time
ワクワクする明日へ
Towards an exciting tomorrow
思い切って
Taking the plunge,
張り切って
Full of energy,
前向いて
Looking ahead,
さあ進もう！
Now, let's move forward!
せーの！
One, two!
いつだって本気で
Always giving it our all
遊び尽くしちゃえ
Let's play to our heart's content
やりすぎちゃうくらいで It's all right
It's all right if we overdo it a bit
早起きよりも
Rather than waking up early,
徹夜しちゃおう
Let's stay up all night
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
Because everything's bound to work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Because a pinch can become a chance
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
If we all laugh together, we're invincible
なんだって全力で
Everything at full power
突き抜けちゃって
Break right through
真っ直ぐな気持ちでいこう
Let's go with straightforward feelings
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, jump, and let's take off!
Yeah!!
順調にいく、だけじゃ
Just going smoothly...
それはそれで退屈だね
...would be boring in its own way
わがままかもしれないけど
It might be selfish, but
失敗は成功の元！
Failure is the mother of success!
とかカッコつけてみたけど
I tried to act cool like that,
やらかしちゃった日の夜は
but on the nights I messed up,
枕に向かって叫んだ
I screamed into my pillow
それもみんなが聴いてくれるから
Because everyone listens to that too,
悪くないよね！
it's not so bad, right!
せーの！
One, two!
今しかできないことをしようよ
Let's do the things that can only be done now
心配ご無用！
No need to worry!
無問題（モーマンタイ）！
No problem!
ありのままで
Just as you are
走る前から
Even before starting to run
つまずくことをハイ！
Don't worry about tripping up, hi!
考えてちゃしょうがない
Thinking about it won't help anything
もしも雨が降ったとしたら
Even if it starts to rain
とっておきの傘を差そうよ
Let's use our favorite umbrella
なんだって全力で突き抜けちゃって！
No matter what, burst through with all your might!
真っ直ぐな気持ちでいこう
Let's go with straightforward feelings
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Leap out with a hop, step, and a jump!
なかなかお布団から
It's hard to get out of bed
出られない日もある
On some days
でも明日から
But from tomorrow...
そう明日から
Yes, from tomorrow...
本気をだすんだ！
I'll give it my all!
気が済むまで日が暮れるまで！
Until you're satisfied, until the sun goes down!
門限なんか無視でイッツオーライ！
Ignore the curfew, it's all right!
早起きよりも徹夜しちゃおう
Instead of waking up early, let's pull an all-nighter
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
Because everything's sure to work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Because a pinch will turn into a chance
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
We're invincible if we all laugh together
なんだって全力で突き抜けちゃって！
No matter what, burst through with all your might!
真っ直ぐな気持ちでいこう
Let's go with straightforward feelings
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Leap out with a hop, step, and a jump!
Yeah!!
はぁ...はぁ...はい！ということで
(Panting) Okay! So...
始まりました、えー
It's started... uh...
こんぬい！ホロライブ三期生の不知火フレアです！
Konnui! I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
はぁ...ちょっと一曲目にね
(Panting) Well, for the first song...
この後すごい沢山踊ると思って、ちょっとラフにいこうと思ったらね
I thought I'd take it easy since I'll be dancing a lot later...
これはこれでしんどかった。めちゃめちゃ回って
...but this was tough in its own way. I spun around so much...
飛び回ってしまった！ということで
...and jumped around everywhere! So...
私、今回、三周年ということでね
This time is my 3rd anniversary...
皆様、私の三周年アニバーサリーライブにお越しいただきまして本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to my 3rd Anniversary Live!
ハッシュタグはこちら、この辺に出てると思うので
The hashtag is here, it should be appearing around here...
こちらのツイートをいっぱいしてください。お写真もバシバシバシバシバシバシ撮ってくれると嬉しいです。
Please tweet a lot about it. I'd also be happy if you took lots and lots of photos.
まぁ今回はですね、あの皆様エルフレンドと私、えーそして今見てくれてる初見の人とかね
Well, this time, for all the Elfriends, myself, and those watching me for the first time...
皆さんの記憶に残るライブの一つになると思うのでね、ぜひぜひ楽しんでくれると嬉しいです。
I hope this will be a live performance that stays in your memories, so please enjoy it!
さてさて、二曲目なんですけど、二曲目は
Now then, about the second song... for the second song...
なんとね、エルフレンドに手伝ってもらおうかなって思うんですよね。ちょっと選ばれしエルフレンドを探したいので
I think I'll have an Elfriend help me out. I want to look for the chosen Elfriend...
カメラさん、クルっと回ってもらっていいですか？
Mr. Cameraman, could you spin the camera around?
どれどれ、どうかな？なんか私の目に叶ういい奴いるかな？
Let's see... how about it? Is there anyone good who catches my eye?
お、君！あ、いいね！君なんか死んだ魚の目をしている。いいじゃないか。
Oh, you! Ah, nice! You have eyes like a dead fish. Not bad at all.
おいで、こっちにおいで。
Come on, come over here.
これはJPニキっぽいね。男の子かな？女の子かな？
This one looks like a Japanese bro. A boy? Or a girl?
まあまあ中性的そうな感じのエルフレンドなわけだけど
They're a rather androgynous-looking Elfriend...
君は男の子？女の子？男の子？
Are you a boy? A girl? A boy?
あ、男の子みたいですね。ということで、じゃあ今回は、エルフレンド、JPニキにお手伝いしていただこうかなと思います。
Ah, it seems he's a boy. So, this time, I'll have the Elfriend JP-niki help me out.
はい代表だからね。はい皆恥じないように、皆に恥じないように頼むで。
You're the representative. Please don't let everyone down, don't embarrass them.
じゃまずね、ちょっと君にはこれをプレゼント。これで君は社会の歯車になるんだ。
First, I have a present for you. With this, you'll become a cog in society.
いいね。じゃあせーので見せるよ。
Great. Now, I'll show it on the count of three.
はい、せーの！くる。
Ready, set... go! (Spin)
ということで、今日はこの二人で一曲奏でようぜ。
And so, today, the two of us will perform a song together.
じゃあ君はこっち。
You, go over here.
はい、ということで、マイクも用意してくれたということでね、じゃあちょっと早速なんですけど二曲目行ってみよう！
Okay, so the microphones are ready, so let's get straight to the second song!
もし！
Hello!
来い来い五合来い凄い来い五合来い来い来い五合来い凄い来い五合来い
Come, come, come! Great, come! Come, come, come! Great, come!
あなたとあなたを
With you, and for you
幸せにする夢の夢のフレアチャンネル！
Making everyone happy, the dream Flare Channel!
僕は社会の歯車
I'm a cog in society
労働環境は中の下の下
My working conditions are the lowest of the low
やりがい搾取給料据え置き
Exploited for "fulfillment", salary stays the same
コンビニアイスが贅沢です
Convenience store ice cream is a luxury
在宅勤務でも社畜！
Even working from home, I'm a corporate slave!
ゆとりも Z 代でも社畜！
Whether from the relaxed generation or Gen Z, I'm a corporate slave!
チクタク似たようなローテーション
Tick-tock, it's the same old rotation
なーんかいいことないかなー
Isn't there something good out there?
「そこのあなた！チャンスです！」
"You there! It's your lucky day!"
チャンネル登録する
Subscribe to the channel
チャンネル登録するだけで
Just by subscribing to the channel,
お届けしましょう
we shall deliver
日々の潤い
daily enrichment.
爆アゲ確定 QOL
Guaranteed boost to your Quality of Life.
これにて解決 Q.E.D.
With this, it's settled. Q.E.D.
はい！不知火コールセンターです！
Hello! Shiranui Call Center here!
「将来が不安で…」
"I'm worried about the future..."
なんとかなるでしょ！
It'll work out somehow!
「なんか寂しいんだ…」
"I feel a bit lonely..."
ゲームしようよ！
Let's play games!
「声が届かない…」
"My voice doesn't reach..."
コメント見てるよ！
I'm reading the comments!
「僕がいなくても…」
"Even if I'm not here..."
君が必要だ！
I need you!
ここに来れば
If you come here,
私はいる
I'll be here.
今日もバカみたいに騒ごうよ
Let's go crazy and have fun today too!
「今ならチャンネル登録、なんと無料！」
"Channel subscription is now absolutely free!"
こんな時代だからこそ
Because we live in such times,
僕と私は出逢えた
you and I were able to meet.
距離も空間も次元も超えて
Transcending distance, space, and dimensions,
同じモーメント過ごしてるって
sharing the same moment...
すごくない？
isn't that amazing?
これはすごいことだよね
This is truly something special.
すごいすごいすごーい！
Amazing, amazing, amazing!
あなたとあなたを
You and you,
幸せにする
I'll make you happy.
夢の夢のフレアチャンネル
The dream, the dream Flare Channel.
「フレアちゃんのおかげでおしゃれに目覚めました。」
"Thanks to Flare-chan, I've awakened to fashion."
「フレアチャンネル見て積みゲークリアできました！」
"Watching Flare Channel helped me clear my backlog of games!"
「フレアチャンネルに入った日に宝くじ当たりました。」
"I won the lottery on the day I joined Flare Channel."
「フレアチャンネルを見始めてから膝が軽くなった気がします」
"Since I started watching Flare Channel, my knees feel lighter."
全てエルフレ個人の感想です♪
These are all personal opinions of Elfriends♪
至近距離で言ってあげる
I'll tell you from up close,
みんなのことほんと大好きだー！
I really love you all!
なんか晴れない世界も
Even in a world that doesn't clear up,
君と僕なら大丈夫さ
with you and me, it'll be alright.
地球爆誕で約5ビリオン
About 5 billion years since the Earth's birth,
やばいガチャ引き当てて出逢えた
I pulled an insane gacha and met you.
やばくない？
Isn't that crazy?
やっぱやばいことだよね
It really is something crazy.
僕が僕でいられる
A place where I can be myself,
そんな場所がここなんだ
that place is right here.
こんな時代だからこそ
Because we live in such times,
僕と私は出逢えた
you and I were able to meet.
距離も空間も次元も超えて
Transcending distance, space, and dimensions,
同じモーメント過ごしてるって
sharing the same moment...
すごくない？
isn't that amazing?
これはすごいことだよね
This is truly something special.
すごいすごいすごーい！
Amazing, amazing, amazing!
あなたとあなたを
You and you,
幸せにする
I'll make you happy.
夢の夢のフレアチャンネル
The dream, the dream Flare Channel.
はーい！ということでね、どうだった？
All right! So, how was it?
社会の歯車からは解放されたかい？
Were you freed from the gears of society?
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
ならよかったねー。
That's good then.
あーよかったよかった。これで明日からもまたね、頑張れるね。
Oh, good, good. Now you can work hard again from tomorrow.
はい、じゃあね、頑張ってくれたこのグラさんのエルフレには
Alright, to this Elfriend with sunglasses who worked so hard...
拍手！盛大な拍手を！
Applause! A big round of applause!
こちらの曲はですね、エルフレンドと私とのデュエット、
This song was a duet between an Elfriend and me,
syudouさんに、なんと作っていただきました！ありがとうございます！
and it was actually created by syudou-san! Thank you very much!
はい、じゃあそのサングラスは記念に持って帰っていいからね。
You can take those sunglasses home as a souvenir.
それを着けて、やる気に満ち溢れる生活を送ってくれよな！
Wear them and lead a life full of motivation!
じゃあ、観客席に戻っておいで！
Now, head back to your seat in the audience!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ま、でもね、ちょっと、やっぱ一人だけなんて、ずるいよなー。
Well, but, having just one person is a bit unfair, isn't it?
なんでね、ま、ちょっと、もうちょっとあの、演奏してもらいたいんですよね、次はね。
So, I'd like a few more people to perform next.
エルフレンド何人か、あの、ステージからお呼びしたいんですけど。
I want to invite several Elfriends onto the stage.
まずは、私がサングラスを取りますね。
First, I'll take off my sunglasses.
もう、次の曲はね、もっと明る… ま、明るかったけど今のも。
The next song is even more bright... well, the last one was bright too.
ま、ちょっとね、あの、次の曲は、私が、君たちエルフレンドを応援する曲をね、
Well, for the next song, I've prepared one to support all of you Elfriends.
送りたいなって思ってました。
I've really wanted to share it with you.
日頃からみんなにね、何かプレゼントしたい、何かお返しできるものはないかなって思っていたので、
I'm always thinking about what I can give back to you all on a daily basis,
今日はそれを、やらせていただきたいなと思います。
so I'd like to do just that today.
なんでね、ちょっと演奏してもらうエルフレンドを何人か呼びさせていただきます。
So, I'll invite a few Elfriends to play for me.
ちょっとカメラをもう一回、くるっと。
Could you turn the camera around again?
あ、君ね、女の子じゃん！
Oh, it's you! You're a girl!
女の子のエルフレも二人。
Two girl Elfriends as well.
あ〜、ハリグラフほしいな。
Ah, I want a polygraph.
あとは、う〜ん。
And then, hmm...
あ、EN、ENでもほしいね。君と君と。
Ah, I want some from EN too. You and you.
あ、JPもやっぱりもうちょっとほしいかな？
Ah, maybe I want a few more from JP too?
君と君と。あ、なんか何物にも縛られていないオーソドックスなエルフレもいるね。
You and you. Oh, there's an orthodox Elfriend who isn't bound by anything.
じゃあ君もおいで。
Well, you come here too.
はい、ということで、彼ら彼女たちにはちょっとね、次の曲を演奏していただこうかなって思います。
So, I'm thinking of having them perform the next song.
準備できた？はい、おいで、おいで。来たね。
Are you ready? Okay, come here, come here. They've arrived.
そしたら、君たちエルフレ、お、なんか花飾り初めてだね。可愛いね。
Now then, you Elfriends... Oh, flower decorations for the first time. Cute!
君たちエルフレンドにもね、やっぱりあの、贈呈品をプレゼントするから。
I'll give you Elfriends a gift too.
これを、みんな、みんなちょっとこれを持ってもらって。
Everyone, everyone please hold this.
はい、はい、はい。はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
はい、できた？これをね、じゃあ持ってもらって次の曲を演奏してもらうわけだけど、いいかい？
Okay, ready? I'll have you hold this and perform the next song, okay?
はい、準備！
Alright, get ready!
あ、いいおね、あ、準備できました！
Ah, looks good! Preparations are complete!
じゃあ、彼ら彼女たちに演奏してもらいつつ...
Well, while they perform...
...私がエルフレンド応援するぞ！
...I'll cheer for the Elfriends!
いきますよ！
Here we go!
「さぁ、今日はエルフレンドのみんなを、応援するぞ！」
"Now, today I'm going to cheer for all the Elfriends!"
「覚悟してね！」
"Get ready!"
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fre! Fre! Elfre!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Go for it, go for it, Elfre!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fre! Fre! Elfre!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Go for it, go for it, Elfre!
オー！
Oh!
朝はちょっとでも寝てたいなんて...
In the morning, I want to sleep just a bit more...
二度寝とスヌーズ、ループしてさ
Oversleeping and snooze, looping...
朝だよ〜！おはよーおはよー
It's morning! Good morning, good morning!
それでも毎朝起きてるキミは
But you who wakes up every morning...
それだけで表彰ものだ！
Just for that, you deserve an award!
えらいぞ〜！よしよしよしよし！
You're doing great! There, there, there, there!
ときには上手くいかずに
Sometimes things don't go well...
凹んでしまうこともあるよね...
And you might feel down, right?
それでもキミと私なら
But with you and me...
きっと It's OK!
It'll surely be It's OK!
乗り越えられるさ
We can overcome it.
「さぁ、張り切っていくよ！」
"Now, let's get pumped up!"
「せーの！」
"One, two!"
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
全力でエール送るよ
Sending cheers with all my might.
Come on!
キミをもっと元気にしたいんだ
I want to make you more energetic.
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
疲れたときは
When you are tired...
いつでもここに来て
Come here any time.
ゆっくり休んだら
After resting slowly...
一緒にまたやっていこうよ
Let's do it again together.
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fre! Fre! Elfre!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Go for it, go for it, Elfre!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fre! Fre! Elfre!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Go for it, go for it, Elfre!
今夜も帰りが遅くて
Returning home late tonight again...
一日すぐ終わっていくね
The day ends so quickly, doesn't it?
「がんばったね！おつぬいおつぬい！」
"You worked hard! Otsunui, otsunui!"
そんな日々の、貴重なひと時を
In such daily life, this precious moment...
一緒にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being with me.
「いつもありがとう！」
"Thank you always!"
平日、夜に大騒ぎ
Making a fuss on a weeknight...
歌って遊んで楽しんでね
Singing, playing, and having fun.
そうして笑顔になったら
And if you end up with a smile...
きっと Smile and go
Surely Smile and go...
またがんばれるよ
You can work hard again.
「めいいっぱい楽しんでいこうー！」
"Let's enjoy it to the fullest!"
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
大丈夫、何でもできるよ
It's okay, you can do anything.
キミともっと夢を描こう
Let's dream more with you.
ファイト！
Fight!
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
だから無理はしないで
So don't overdo it.
いつでも止まり木においでよ
Come to the perch any time.
そっからまた始めよう
Let's start from there again.
日々のしんどさはループでも
Even if the daily hardships are a loop...
楽しさはきっとスパイラル
The fun will surely be a spiral.
思い出っていう宝物手にしたら
If you hold the treasure called memories...
明日も怖くないよ
Tomorrow won't be scary either.
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
全力でエール送るよ
Sending cheers with all my might.
キミをもっと元気にしたいんだ
I want to make you more energetic.
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
疲れたときは
When you are tired...
いつでもここに来て
Come here any time.
ゆっくり休んだら
After resting slowly...
一緒にまたやっていこうよ
Let's do it again together.
ぬい！ぬい！ぬい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fre! Fre! Elfre!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Go for it, go for it, Elfre!
フレ！フレ！...
Fre! Fre!...
エルフレ！エルフレ！
Elfriend! Elfriend!
ガンバレガンバレ　エルフレ！オー！
Do your best, do your best, Elfriend! Oh!
イェーイ！ふー！
Yay! Whoo!
いつもありがとう！
Thank you as always!
愛してるぞー！
I love you guys!
はい、ということで...
Alright, so...
あ、エルフレンドのみんな、オイスタオイスタ！
Oh, Elfriends, Oisuta Oisuta!
でもね、まだまだ続きますからね！
But you know, there's still more to come!
今回歌わせていただいた曲は、ヒゲドライバーさんに作っていただきましたー！
The song I just performed was written by Hige Driver!
エルフレンドをね、元気に応援したいなって思っていたので、
I really wanted to give the Elfriends a cheerful boost,
もう理想的な曲ができたかなって思っています。
so I think it turned out to be the perfect song.
エルフレンドの君たちはどうだった？
What did you Elfriends think of it?
エモくて、あ、え、泣いてる？泣いちゃった？
It was emotional... oh? Are you crying? Did you cry?
なんちゃって！
Just kidding!
はい、ありがとうございます。
Anyway, thank you very much.
や、あの、演奏してくれたみんなもね、ありがとね！
And thank you to everyone who performed as well!
ありがとね、ありがとね、うん！
Thank you, thank you! Yeah!
あ、ちょっと、あ、やばい。
Ah, wait, ah, oh no.
女の子のエルフレンドにうつつを抜かしてごめんね。ありがとありがと。みんなありがとね！
Sorry for getting distracted by the girl Elfriends. Thanks, thanks. Thank you everyone!
ま、まだまだね、あの、今回他にもたくさん曲歌うので、
Well, there's still more. I'll be singing many other songs today,
今、演奏してくれたみんなもね、一旦ね、あの、客席の方にお戻りいただいて、
so everyone who performed just now, please return to your seats for a moment,
次の曲をね、待ってほしいかなと思います！
and I hope you look forward to the next song!
演奏してくれたエルフレンドたちに盛大な拍手を！
A big round of applause for the Elfriends who performed!
ありがとー！ありがとー！
Thank you! Thank you!
ふーふーふー！
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
行った？行った？
Did they go? Did they go?
あ、行っちゃった。これはこれで寂しいね。
Ah, they're gone. This is a bit lonely in its own way.
でもね、ちゃんと前にもね、エルフレンドが二人演奏したり、あ、ぼーっとしたりとかしてくれてるので、
But you see, there are two Elfriends in front of me, performing... or just spacing out,
え、私寂しくない。
so I'm not lonely.
僕にも...あ、あそこにも小さなエルフレがなんかいましたね。小さな。
Even for me... oh, there was a tiny Elfriend over there too. A tiny one.
エルフレンドが見えましたね。はい。
I could see an Elfriend. Yes.
じゃあね、エルフレンドみんなね、いっぱいペンライト振る仕事、よろしくお願いしますよ！
So, Elfriends, please do your job of waving those penlights a lot!
はい！ではね、次はですね、お待ちかねかと思うので、
Alright! Next up, since I think it's what you've been waiting for,
あの曲を、ゲストのみんなと歌っちゃおうかなって思います！
I'm going to sing THAT song with some guests!
ゲストっつってもね、ま、わかってるね！
Even when I say guests, well, you already know!
三期生のみんなと一緒にあの曲を歌うぞー！
I'm going to sing that song with all the 3rd gen members!
いってみよー！
Let's go!
こんぬいー！準備はいいかー？今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！せーの！
Kon-nui! Are you ready? Let's make some noise together today! One, two!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイ！イェーイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai! Yay!
Smile & Go!
作詞・作曲・編曲：渡辺あきと / 桃流浩純
Lyrics/Music/Arrangement: Akito Watanabe / Hirozumi Momoru
やってきました　みんなに会える時間です
The time has finally come for us to meet everyone
歌とかゲームとか見てほしくて
I want you to see our songs and games
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に
In these days that seem to pass in the blink of an eye
乗り遅れないように手繋ごう
Let's hold hands so we don't get left behind
気付けば隣にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being by my side before I knew it
どんな高い壁だってひとっ飛びで飛び越えて
We'll leap over even the highest walls in one bound
誰も見たことない世界に　みんなで行こうよ
Let's all go together to a world no one has ever seen
君と Smile & Go! 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go! The one who has fun wins
君と Smile & Go! ハジけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go! The one who lets loose wins
ここに笑顔で
With a smile here
集まれば
When we gather
最高でしょ！
It's the best, right!
僕ら Smile & Go! いつも全力で
We, Smile & Go! Always with all our might
僕ら Smile & Go! 遊びまくろう
We, Smile & Go! Let's play our hearts out
だって
Because
そうさ
That's right
この日常が　大切な宝物だよ
This everyday life is a precious treasure
Smile & Go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイ！イェーイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai! Yay!
雑談配信　今日はまったり行きましょう
Chit-chat stream, let's take it easy today
たわいない話　聞いてほしくて
I want you to hear our trivial talk
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど
I thought about taking a break once in a while
やっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな
But maybe I'll do a late-night drinking stream after all
ありふれたこの時も　一緒に過ごしたいな
I want to spend even these ordinary moments with you
いつの間にかキラキラと　何よりも輝いて
Before I knew it, it's sparkling and shining more than anything
言葉にはできない思いが　溢れ出しちゃうよ
Feelings that can't be put into words are overflowing
君と Let's Enjoy! 歌ってみようよ
With you, Let's Enjoy! Let's try singing
君と Let's Enjoy! 心はひとつに
With you, Let's Enjoy! Our hearts are as one
どこにいたって
No matter where you are
優しさは届いてるよ
The kindness is reaching you
僕ら Let's Enjoy! テンション上げてさ
We, Let's Enjoy! Let's get hyped up
僕ら Let's Enjoy! はしゃぎまくろう
We, Let's Enjoy! Let's frolic around
きっと
Surely
そうさ
That's right
明日はもっと　楽しいこと待っているから
Because more fun things are waiting for us tomorrow
みんな！3周年ありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for the 3rd anniversary!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ここからはダンスパートだ！
From here it's the dance part!
フレア、いつもサンキューな！
Flare, thanks as always!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
フレア、これからもよろしく！
Flare, looking forward to the future too!
よろしく！
Likewise!
フレア、チュチュ！
Flare, chu chu!
チュチュ！
Chu chu!
一緒に来たよー！
We came together!
あ、一緒に！
Ah, together!
みんな、いくよ！一緒に！
Everyone, here we go! Together!
せーの！
Ready, set...
3, 2, 1, GO!
ずっと見ていて　私のことを
Keep watching me forever
これから先も　期待してね
Keep your expectations high for the future too
予測不能な　ワクワクを君に　贈るから
Because I'll send you unpredictable excitement
君とSmile & Go!!
With you, Smile & Go!!
楽しんだもん勝ち
The one who enjoys it wins
君とSmile & Go!!
With you, Smile & Go!!
ハジけたもん勝ち
The one who bursts with energy wins
ここに笑顔で　集まれば
If we gather here with smiles
最高でしょ　イェーイ！
It's the best, right? Yay!
僕らSmile & Go!!　いつも全力で
We Smile & Go!! Always with all our might
僕らSmile & Go!!　遊びまくろう
We Smile & Go!! Let's play our hearts out
だって　そうさ　この日常が　大切な
Because, that's right, this everyday life is a precious
宝物だよ
Treasure
とびきりの　笑顔で行こう
Let's go with our best smiles
Smile and Go!!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey hey!
イェーイ！
Yay!
何しようか練習中
Thinking about what to do while practicing
しれっとこっそり準備進行
Stealthily making preparations
心境　緊張　手汗る
Mental state: nervous, hands getting sweaty
いわんや強々ありでしょ
Not to mention, being strong is fine too, right?
元気配るから待っちょって
I'll share some energy, so please wait
そうやって成長する子です
That's how this girl grows
いいかな？
Is that okay?
ゆるポンでOK
Relaxed is OK
1, 2, 3
テンパっちゃってOK
Getting panicked is OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
ほめてほしいな
I want to be praised
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type who grows by being showered with praise
もー！
Geez!
何も出てこない
Nothing is coming out
頭ん中真っ白ださっぱりだ
My head is completely blank, totally empty
んんん？あれ？
Hmm? Wait?
まいっか！
Oh well!
デコボコな情緒　低空飛行
Bumpy emotions, flying low
ポカンとして何しよんの？
Dazed, what are you doing?
困難が通常のアタシ
Difficulties are the norm for me
いいでしょ？
It's fine, right?
それではOK
Well then, OK
1, 2, 3
落ち着きOK
Calmness is OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
どうしたらいいの？
What should I do?
どうすればみんなハッピーで笑顔バッチリ
What should I do so everyone is happy and smiling perfectly
こちらへどうぞ
This way, please
押さず慌てず並んで合図です
Line up without pushing or rushing, that's the signal
もー！
Geez!
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
みゃみゃみゃ
Mya mya mya
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
ぽんぽんぽん
Pon pon pon
こっちだよ！
Over here!
少し眠いな
I'm a little sleepy
また明日　食べて寝て　今は成長期
See you tomorrow, eating and sleeping, it's my growing period
夢を見たいな
I want to have a dream
どうぞこれからも　あの今後も
Please, from now on and in the future too
ほめてほしいな
I want to be praised
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
ほめちぎられて伸びる
I'm the type who grows
タイプです
by being praised to the skies.
またね！
See you!
はーい！
Hi!
最高！拍手！
That was great! Applause!
電池がね、切れちまったということで。
The battery... seems to have run out.
フレア～！
Flare!
ノエル～！
Noel!
あ～、大好きだよ。
Ah, I love you.
ちょっと、いつもフレアにさ、そういうのされてるからさ。
Hey, since I'm always having Flare do that to me...
団長もね、ちょっとやりたいなと思って。
I thought I'd like to try it too.
いや、この度はおめでとうございます。今回のライブ。
Well, congratulations on today's live concert.
ありがと～。
Thank you.
いや、めっちゃかっこいいじゃん、何？スカイソナー。
You look so cool. What's this? SKYSONAR.
ソナーだよ。今日はおしゃれに青空をテーマにしてみました。
It's SONAR. I went for a stylish blue sky theme today.
青い空、そして海。
Blue sky, and the sea.
やっぱりね、うちらがデビューしたのが夏、真っ盛りでさ。
After all, we debuted in the height of summer.
そうなんだよね。
That's right.
いや眩しい、眩しすぎて溶ける、溶けちまうぜ。
It's so bright, so bright I'm gonna melt, I'm melting!
お前もその一部なんだぜ！
You're part of it too!
いや本当さ、すごいエモいんですけど、
No, seriously, it's really emotional.
え、この中だと団長はこの、あ、これしてる？
Wait, in this, is Noel doing... oh, this?
そうだよ。
Yeah.
いや、なんかいいね、でもね、あれ多分ね、誰にも当たってないからね、
Well, it's nice. But you know, that probably didn't hit anyone,
遠洋がそっと。
it's just drifting off into the open sea.
そんな、辛辣すぎないか？
Isn't that a bit too harsh?
いや、いいね、ちょっとあれですよ、4周年目もね、辛辣でよろしくお願いします。
Well, it's good. Please keep being harsh for the 4th anniversary too.
漫才ですか？漫才始まってんね。
Is this a comedy routine? The routine's started.
いや、本当におめでとうございます。
Well, seriously, congratulations.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
いやなんかさ、ほめのに、めちゃくちゃオンギャル曲やないですか？
You know, isn't "Homenobi" such a great girl song?
あ、ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you.
なんか結構ね、ホロメンが歌枠とかで歌ってくれて。
Quite a few Hololive members have been singing it in their singing streams.
いやまさか、フレアとこうやって二人で歌って踊れるなんて思わなかった。
I never thought I'd be able to sing and dance with Flare like this.
いやそりゃ、この日のためにね、決して今まで歌わなかったわけじゃないですよ。
Well, of course. It's not like I haven't sung it until now for this day.
いやちょっと待って...あ、そうだね、この日のためにとっておいた。
Wait a minute... Oh, right. I saved it for today.
あ、なるほど、いやいいこと言いますね。
Oh, I see. Well said.
わけではないんですけどね。申し訳ありません。
That's not exactly it, though. Sorry.
なんかそう言うと、ちょっと変わってくるからね。
If you say it like that, it sounds a bit different.
いや、歌ってなかったから、焦って歌ったんかみたいになっちゃうからね。
It'll make it look like I sang it in a rush because I hadn't sung it yet.
違う、違う、違う。
No, no, no.
ちょっと距離感が。
The distance between us is a bit...
ハイ、ナ、ナ、ナ、ナ、ナ、ナ、ほめほめ。
Hi, na, na, na, na, na, na, praise, praise.
これ実際踊るとなかなか合わないの、ここ。
When we actually dance this, it's hard to sync up here.
ここね。
Right here.
いなっ、いなっ。
Wait, wait.
あ、でもここさ、あれかもしれない、エルフレのみんなとか団員さんが、
Oh, but maybe this part, all the Elfriends and Dan-in-san...
あ、ここに間にね、いるかもしれない。
Oh, they might be in the gap here.
寄せないけど。
I'm not moving closer though.
そうだね。びしゃ、寄せないけどね、って。あ～い。
Right. Splash, but I'm not moving closer. Ah-i.
いや、本当にエモいな。
Man, this is really emotional.
でしょう。
Isn't it?
エモすぎる。あ、みんなで写真撮っておく？
Too emotional. Oh, should we take a photo with everyone?
あの団員さん、じゃ...
The Dan-in-san... then...
団員さん！ねえ！
Dan-in-san! Hey!
そうやって、団員さんのことばっかり大切にして！団長のことなんて、もう忘れちゃうんでしょ！
You're always putting the Dan-in-san first! You're going to forget all about me, aren't you!
あ、間に合った。間に合った。大丈夫。
Oh, I made it. I made it. It's okay.
団員さんね。団員さんとエルフレンドと、
The Dan-in-san. With the Dan-in-san and Elfriends...
じゃ、写真撮るか。
well, let's take a photo.
ちょっと脳が破壊されたところだった。あは、じゃないんだよ。
My brain was just about to break. It's not "aha"!
はい、ピース！イエーイ！
Say cheese! Yay!
まだまだ続くのね。
It's still going on.
そう、まだまだ続くからね。
Yes, it's still going on.
じゃ、はい、ピース、見てね！
Well, say cheese! Watch us!
まだまだ続くぞ！イエーイ！
It's still going! Yay!
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆
Ahoy!! Warera Houshou Kaizokudan
海賊ならヨーホー
If you're a pirate, yo-ho!
踊れ叫べヨーホー
Dance and shout, yo-ho!
さあ、今、旗の下
Now, under the flag...
宝鐘海賊団...
The Houshou Pirates...
出航！
Set sail!
踊るアホイに見るアホイ！
The dancing ahoy and the watching ahoy!
全速前進だ！
Full speed ahead!
進め！
Advance!
太陽燦々大航海日和だ
A sunny day, perfect for a grand voyage.
歌え！
Sing!
最高のテンション波の音に乗せてドンブラコ
With the best tension, bobbing on the waves.
海辺でガールズトーク おかげでアニキがハッピー
Girls' talk by the seaside makes the brothers happy.
お空も青々 ヒラヒラ
The sky is so blue, fluttering.
山奥ボロボロマイハウスで夢を見て
Dreaming in my raggedy house deep in the mountains.
あぁ、神様、いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にしてやってください！
Oh, God, please make this Marine a real pirate someday!
おい！
Hey!
声を上げて さあ出航だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voice, let's set sail! We're the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
With compass in hand and flag raised, let's jack this sea!
よそ見せずについておいで 共にヨーホーヨーホー叫ぼう
Follow along without looking away! Let's shout yo-ho, yo-ho together!
最高の日々へようこそ我が船
Welcome to the best days on our ship!
踊るアホイに見るアホイ！
The dancing ahoy and the watching ahoy!
1, 2, 3, サンバ！
1, 2, 3, Samba!
熱く語ろうよ パッション 思いを解き放て
Let's talk passionately, passion, release your feelings.
紅く揺らめく ファッション 形から入るタイプです
Crimson flickering fashion, I'm the type who starts with appearance.
発射 10秒前 走れ ガチ恋列車
Launch! 10 seconds to go. Run, Gachikoi Train.
夕焼けも照れるわ キラキラ
Even the sunset is blushing. Sparkling.
じんわり汗も滴るいい女 だけど
A fine woman dripping with sweat, but...
ああ 神様 船長はセンシティブだと BANされちゃうのですね はにゃ〜
Ah, God, if the captain is too sensitive, she'll get banned, won't she? Hanya~!
奪われたなら 取り戻せ それが宝鐘海賊団だ
If it's stolen, take it back. That's the Houshou Pirates.
君たちとなら たどり着ける 伝説のエルドラド
With you all, we can reach the legendary El Dorado.
野郎ども 楽しけりゃ 歌えヨーホーホー 足りない ああ この景色
Mates, if you're having fun, sing Yo-ho-ho! It's not enough, ah, this view.
大切な仲間よ
My precious comrades.
宴だ宴だ 騒げや騒げ
It's a banquet! It's a banquet! Make some noise!
踊るアホウに見るアホウ
Fools dancing and fools watching.
同じアホなら呑まなきゃ損損
If we're all fools, it's a loss not to drink.
高々掲げた手に行きますよ そーれ アホイ！
Higher and higher, here we go! Ahoy!
アホイ！アホイ！アホイ！アホイ！...
Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! ...
宝鐘マリン！ 宝鐘マリン！
Houshou Marine! Houshou Marine!
世界で一番かわいいよー！
You're the cutest in the world!
メスガキ！メスガキ！
Mesugaki! Mesugaki!
エロガキ！エロガキ！
Erogaki! Erogaki!
ボン・キュッ・ボン！ ボン・キュッ・ボン！
Bon-kyu-bon! Bon-kyu-bon!
お嬢ちゃんパンツ何色？ パンツ履いてませーん！
Little girl, what color are your panties? I'm not wearing any!
お宝 お宝！
Treasure, treasure!
覗い 覗い！
Peep, peep!
撫でますドン！
Nademasu don!
船長の… ちょっといいとこ… 見てみたい〜！
Captain's... good points... I want to see them~!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
セクシービーム！ もっと！もっと！
Sexy Beam! More! More!
だっちゅーの！ もっと！もっと！
Dacchuno! More! More!
サービスサービス！ もっと！もっと！
Service service! More! More!
萌え萌えきゅん！ もっと！もっと！
Moe moe kyun! More! More!
出会って5秒で即出航〜！
Set sail instantly, 5 seconds after meeting!
ああ もう 船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません 本当に メッ！だぞ
Ah, really... I don't remember raising you guys to be like that. Honestly, you're bad!
立てば痴女 座れば昭和 歩く姿はセンシティブ
Standing, she's a nympho. Sitting, she's Showa era. Walking, she's sensitive.
夢を見よう この船で 後悔なんてさせない
Let's dream on this ship. I won't let you regret it.
君たちのおかげで 私は船長になれるから
Because of you all, I can be the captain.
ミラクル船長大砲、撃て！ パッヒーン！
Miracle Captain Cannon, fire! Pah-heen!
声を上げて さあ出航だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団だ
Raise your voices, now set sail! We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
With a compass in hand and flag raised, let's jack this sea!
野郎ども ついておいで ともにヨーホーホー 叫ぼう ああ 最高の日々
Mates, follow me! Let's shout Yo-ho-ho together! Ah, the best days!
ようこそ我が船へ 宝鐘の海賊団
Welcome to my ship, the Houshou Pirates!
それでは行きますよ！ 出航〜！ ヨーソロー！
Well then, here we go! Set sail~! Yoshi-soro!
ああ 気持ちよかった〜
Ah, that felt good~
ああ ちょっとさぁ 船長のセリフでしょ 最後の「我ら」は！
Ah, hey wait a minute. The last "We" was supposed to be my line!
いや なんか やっぱさ 私の船かなって気がしちゃって
Well, I just felt like it was my ship after all.
ちょっと お前の船なんて持ってないんです！
Wait, you don't even have a ship!
ちょっと勘違いしちゃったわ 気持ちよすぎて
I just got a bit confused because it felt so good.
それでは行きますよ！ 出航〜！
Well then, here we go! Set sail~!
声デカいな ちょっと
Your voice is a bit loud.
いや フレア おめでとう 3周年
Anyway, Flare, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary.
ありがとう〜
Thank you~
マリンももうすぐじゃん
It's almost Marine's turn too, right?
あ そうなんだよね
Ah, that's right.
すぐそこだからね
It's coming up soon.
私たち3期生は みんなね デビューが近いからね
All of us 3rd gens have debuts close to each other.
3年経ってみて思うけどさぁ
Now that 3 years have passed, I've been thinking...
なんか フレアと最近 遠いって感じる...
I feel like Flare and I have been distant lately...
でも遠くしたのはお前やろ 船長！
But you're the one who distanced yourself, Captain!
うるさい そんなことないよね
Shut up, that's not true!
最近ね なんかラミィと仲が良いとか
Lately, you've been getting close with Lamy or something.
いつも声かけてんの船長ばっかりな気がする
I feel like the one always calling out is only the Captain.
え そんなことないよ
Eh, that's not true.
なんか船長ばっかり声かけてる気がする
I feel like only the Captain is calling out.
そんなことないよ
That's not true.
でもね なんか マリンは都合の良い女にしか話しかけないからね
But you know, Marine only talks to "convenient" women.
何そのズボッ… やめろやめろ どういう意味や
What's with that blunt... stop it, stop it. What do you mean?
船長 まぁそれはそれとして
Anyway, Captain, setting that aside.
あ それはそれとしてね
Ah, setting that aside.
時間がね ないからね
Because we don't have time.
あ はいはい
Ah, yes yes.
ほら お泊まりの時にさぁ
You know, during the sleepover.
『アホイ』をさ 歌ったことがあるんだけど
We've sung "Ahoy" before.
歌った歌った オフでね
We did, we did. Offline.
実はこんなちゃんと歌ったの初めてで
Actually, it's the first time we've sung it properly like this.
ちゃんとこうやってパートを分けて しっかりとね
Splitting the parts properly like this, firmly.
そうそう しかもね 絶対Cパート真面目に歌わないっていうね
Right right, and also, we absolutely don't sing the C part seriously.
なんか あの… さ 決まらないんだよね どっちか
Like, it doesn't really settle on either...
『立てば痴女』のパートのあの声何ですか ちょっと あの声何やねん
What was that voice in the "Standing, she's a nympho" part? What was that voice?
え だってそういう風に歌って マリンが...
Eh, because singing it that way, Marine...
あそこ森本レオだからね 言っとくけど
That was Leo Morimoto, just so you know.
え 似てない？ 『立てば痴女 座れば昭和』
Eh, doesn't it sound like him? "Standing, nympho. Sitting, Showa."
立てば痴女。
Standing, she's a pervert.
座れば痴女。
Sitting, she's a pervert.
歩く姿は全裸。
And walking, she's totally naked.
ちょ、そんなんじゃなかったさっき！
Wait, it wasn't like that earlier!
え？どういうこと？
Eh? What do you mean?
立てば痴女、みたいな感じだったじゃん。
It was like "standing, she's a pervert."
え、変だった？
Eh, was it weird?
面白かったよｗ
It was funny! lol
いやー、これはリベンジしないといけないね、フレア。
Man, we've gotta get revenge for this, Flare.
またどっかで一回やらないと。
We've gotta do it again somewhere.
そうだね、また来年リベンジしようね。
Yeah, let's get revenge again next year.
なんで来年なん？ねえねえ。
Why next year? Hey, hey.
別に来年じゃなくても今年中にまだまだリベンジできるよね。
It doesn't have to be next year, we can still get revenge within this year.
え、本当に？マリンやる気あるの？
Eh, really? Marine, are you motivated?
あるよ！ほら、こんなに近くにいる。
I am! Look, I'm this close.
よく考えて、マリンさ、今年さコラボしたっけ？
Think carefully, Marine... did we collab this year?
したよ！時系列的に言うともうマリフレお泊まり会があった後だからね、ここは。
We did! In terms of timeline, it's after the Mari-Flare sleepover party.
ああ、じゃあ今年一回やったかも。
Ah, then we might have done it once this year.
まだやるな。ねえ、これからもこれからもやらないと。
Do it again. Hey, we have to do it from now on too.
ペコマリ義務コラボする前にマリフレ義務コラボしないと。
Before the Peko-Mari compulsory collab, we have to do the Mari-Flare one.
義務じゃないよねｗ
It's not an obligation! lol
じゃあマリンの義務に付き合います。
Fine, I'll go along with Marine's obligation.
義務って言わないで！どうしたの冷たいお姉さん。
Don't call it an obligation! What's wrong, cold big sister?
お嬢さん、みんなと写真撮ろっか。
Young lady, shall we take a photo with everyone?
え、あっち？
Eh, over there?
あっちあっち。そう。
That way, that way. Yeah.
はい、チーズ。イエーイ。
Say cheese! Yay!
義務マリフレでしたー。
That was Compulsory Mari-Flare!
なんのこっちゃ！
What the heck!
じゃあ、次が、次は、誰ですか？
Well then, next... who is next?
ぺこちゃんのところに...
To Peko-chan's place...
ぺこちゃんのところに...出港！
To Peko-chan's place... sets sail!
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
いいわけバニー
Iiwake Bunny
なんとかなんないかな
Isn't there anything I can do?
隣のアイツが邪魔だなぁ
The guy next door is a nuisance
宣戦必勝絶対
Winning the declared war, absolutely
今日は昨日とは違うの　なんだって競争
Today is different from yesterday, it's a competition
苦手だそういうの　なんだか寂しい気持ちは私もさ
I'm not good at that... I feel a bit lonely too
先手必勝全速　パレード好きですか？
Winning with the first move at full speed, do you like parades?
あの子にゃ負けないってば　だって誇らしい
I won't lose to that girl, after all, I'm proud
欲張りめ　横取りか？してやります！
Greedy person! Stealing? I'll show you!
言わなきゃってわかってる
I know I have to say it
ああでもない　こうでもない　夢にしましょう
Not this way, not that way, let's make it a dream
つらぬけ　マイ　マイ　マイ
Carry it through, my, my, my
聞きたくない　いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it, Excuse Bunny
地団駄の優柔不断だん　だん
Stomping indecision, dan, dan
バニバニダリダリ　マジな話どっち？
Bunny bunny dally dally, seriously, which one?
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
ダメダメダメ　よそ見しないで
No, no, no, don't look away
ダメダメダメ　逃げ出したい
No, no, no, I want to run away
のは私の方でしょ？
But that's my side, right?
どうしません反対方向
What should we do, opposite direction
ワンツースリー　いいわけバニー
One, two, three, Excuse Bunny
態度はいいわ　話題得意
My attitude is good, I'm good at topics
興味がねえから　超苦手
I'm not interested, so I'm super bad at it
人込み君探す
Searching for you in the crowd
張り紙　届け祈り
Poster, may my prayer reach you
嫉妬私並んで微笑み
Jealousy, me smiling side-by-side
段違いのタフさキャットファイター
Unequalled toughness, catfighter
前進あるのみ　トラブルエナジー
Only moving forward, trouble energy
スカイゾナー　アンズチ　やっちまいなさい
SkySonar Anzuchi, go and do it!
疲れちゃった　ひと休み
I'm tired, taking a break
なんとかねやってよね
Do something about it, okay?
明日の私　任せろ　マイ　マイ　マイ
Leave it to tomorrow's me, my, my, my
決められない　いいわけバニー
I can't decide, Excuse Bunny
有耶無耶です　言いが独擅場
It's vague, a one-man show of talk
メニメニマニマニ　ガチな話ハウマッチ？
Many many, money many, seriously, how much?
ハウマッチ！お利口様
How much! Good child
ダメダメダメ　朝飯前です
No, no, no, it's a piece of cake
ダメダメダメ　そんなのってない
No, no, no, there's no such thing
私一途なほう
I'm the devoted type
マイスイート　逃がさない
My sweet, I won't let you get away
どこへだって行けばいい
Go wherever you want
言い訳ない　容赦しない
No excuses, no mercy
今日じゃない
Not today
ぶつけろ　マイ　マイ　マイ
Throw it, my, my, my
聞きたくない　いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it, Excuse Bunny
地団駄の優柔不断だん　だん
Stomping indecision, dan, dan
バニバニダリダリ　マジな話どっち？
Bunny bunny dally dally, seriously, which one?
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
ダメダメダメ　よそ見しないで
No, no, no, don't look away
ダメダメダメ　逃げ出したい
No, no, no, I want to run away
けどやるしかないでしょ？
But I have to do it, right?
どうしません反対方向
What should we do, opposite direction
ワンツースリー　いいわけバニー
One, two, three, Excuse Bunny
ねえ、最後のハート合ってないよ、ぺこら！
Hey, that last heart didn't line up, Pekora!
いやいやいや、ここのこのダンスはさ、
No, no, no! For this part of the dance,
フレアがたまに気持ちよくなってもう
you sometimes get so carried away
こうなっちゃってたじゃん。
that you end up like this.
改めまして、フレア、3周年おめでとう！
Once again, Flare, happy 3rd anniversary!
ありがとう！ぺこらもおめでとう！
Thank you! Congrats to you too, Pekora!
ありがとうぺこ！
Thanks peko!
いや、3期生はさ、みんなこのタイミングだからね。
Well, for the 3rd gen, we're all reaching it around this time.
え、そ、ぺこらだよね。
Um, yeah, it's Pekora's turn, right?
ね。いや、おめでたい。夏はね、熱いぺこだね、やっぱりね。
Yeah. It's truly a celebration. Summer is hot peko, as expected.
熱いね。気持ちも高ぶるわけですよ。
It's hot. It gets our spirits high.
いや、ぺこらたちも3周年本当、いや、マジで早いよね。
Yeah, Pekora and the others too, 3rd anniversary... honestly, time really flies.
早い！もう3年も経ったの、活動して。
It's fast! It's already been three years since we started our activities.
そうだね。
That's right.
いや、なんかな、フレアとぺこらがさ、
Actually, Flare and Pekora...
なんだ、これ結構話してもいい感じぺこ？
is it okay if I talk about this peko?
いいよ、いいよ。
Sure, go ahead.
なんか、ぺこらがすごいフレアとさ、最初にコラボしたのなんだか覚えてる？
Do you remember what Pekora's very first collab with you was?
マイクラ？
Minecraft?
そう！マイクラぺこ！火薬集めぺこ！懐かしい！
Yes! Minecraft peko! Collecting gunpowder peko! How nostalgic!
ねー。
Right?
そう、ぺこらさ、あの頃はなんだ、
Yeah, Pekora... back then, we were both
マイクラともにさ、初心者だったよね、あの、初めてだったもんね。
beginners at Minecraft, it was our first time.
そう、そう、そう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
なのにな、今となってはさ、ぺこらたちも結構な、なかなかマイクラやってる達人になってるからぺこね。
And yet, look at us now! We've both become quite the Minecraft masters peko.
でも私も言わせてもらっていい？あの時のぺこらはさ、めちゃめちゃ過激でさ、
But may I say something too? Pekora back then was really extreme.
過激！？
Extreme!?
今、すっかり丸くなっちまったな。
You've completely mellowed out now.
ちょっと待てよ。
Wait a second!
おい、それおかしくねーぺこ？私がしてたぺこらは、
Hey, isn't that a bit weird peko? The Pekora I knew
あれ、もう、ウンディーゲーターの巣にマグマを流し込むみたいな、
would do things like pouring lava into the vindicator's nest
あーいうことを平気でやっちゃうやつだったんだけど、今はね、
without a second thought. But now, it's all
『みんなで探検行くぺこー』みたいな、すっかり丸くなりやがって。
'Let's go exploring everyone peko~'. You've totally mellowed out on me.
いや、ちょっと待つぺこよ！いや、前はぺこらも過激なところあるぺこよ。
Hey, wait a peko! I still have my extreme moments peko.
ある、あるでしょ？
I do, right?
丸くなってるよ。
You've mellowed.
そうだな。TNT爆弾ぐらいかな。
I guess... maybe like a TNT bomb.
おい！なんで！？なんかちょっと過激なことやらなきゃいけねーぺこ。
Hey! Why!? I feel like I need to do something extreme peko.
意外と自分やってると思ったぺこだけど、でもね、でもね、なんか、
I thought I was doing quite a lot, actually. But you know, but you know,
あの、最近とかね、ぺこちゃんと一緒にさ、
recently, Peko-chan and I,
あの、突発的だけどさ、あれやったじゃない。
it was spontaneous, but we did that thing.
モンハン？
Monster Hunter?
そう、モンハンもやってじゃん。めっちゃ楽しかった。
Yes, we played Monster Hunter too. It was so much fun.
え、ね、楽しかったよね。となかなかさ、コラボそんな二人でとかしないぺこだしさ。
Yeah, it really was. We don't often do collabs with just the two of us peko.
なんかね、多分、二人共、そんなにコミュ強じゃないから、
Maybe it's because we're both not exactly social butterflies, so
予定立てるっていうのが苦手なんじゃないかな。
making plans is something we're bad at.
いや、あんたはさ、コミュ強じゃない？あんたは…
Hey, aren't you a social butterfly? You're...
違う違う、だって誘えてないじゃん。
No, no, I haven't even been able to invite you.
あ、確かに誘われてない。確かにそれはそうだ。
Ah, true, I haven't been invited. That's true.
そうなんだよ。だから、なんかあの、来て、来てくれるかな、チラチラみたいな感じなんだよ、二人共。
That's how it is. So, it's like we're both glancing over, wondering 'Will they come if I ask?'
あ、そうだね。しかもさ、なんだっけ、フレアのあのこの前のライブのときもさ、
Ah, that's right. And also, what was it, at your previous live too,
あの、『今年はコラボできるといいね』とか言ってたぺこじゃん。
you were saying 'It would be nice if we could collab this year' peko.
いや、マジ今年一回をさ、絶対さ、タイマンでやろうぺこよ。
Seriously, let's definitely do a one-on-one at least once this year peko.
やりたいね。
I'd love to.
絶対だよ。これ約束ね。もうチラチラしないで誘ってくれよ。
Definitely. It's a promise. Don't just glance over, invite me!
いや、あんたこそ誘えないぺこ、いや、私だって。誘う、誘う。
No, you're the one who can't invite peko... I mean, me too. I'll invite you.
よろしくお願いします。じゃあ、そろそろ…
Looking forward to it. Well, it's about time...
そうだね、もう時間なんで。あ、写真。イエーイ！
True, it's time. Oh, the photo. Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
野うさぎ、撮って！
Nousagi, take a picture!
野うさぎ！？あ、こっち、こっちで写真撮って、解散しよう。
Nousagi!? Ah, here, let's take a photo here and then head out.
OK。
OK.
じゃあ、はい、イエーイ！ぺこぺこ！
Okay, then, yay! Peko peko!
ということで、そろそろお時間ですかね。じゃあ、森お帰り？
So, it's about time. Well, heading back to the forest?
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
これで、ぺこら、ぺこぺこぺこ…
With this, Pekora, peko peko peko...
ユグドラシル
作詞・作曲：鈴守志央（未来古代楽団）
Yggdrasil
Lyrics/Comp: Shio Suzumori (MIRA KODAI GAKUDAN)
世界の果ての
At the end of the world,
大いなる樹の麓より
from the foot of the great tree,
永遠の果てへ
to the edge of eternity,
旅立つは歌声
my singing voice departs.
季節は巡りて
The seasons turn,
種はいつか芽生えて
and the seeds will one day sprout.
見守り 見送り
Watching over, seeing off,
花は実を残す
the flowers leave their fruit behind.
時の水面に
Upon the water's surface of time,
消えてゆく名を
the names that fade away,
ただ一人だけ覚えていよう
I will be the only one to remember them.
ここに…
Right here...
ここに誰かが
Someone was here
確かにいたと
For sure, they were
古の調べは
The ancient melody
明日も歌うだろう
Will likely sing tomorrow too
海原を行く
Traveling across the ocean
風を追う海賊の譚詩（バラッド）
The ballad of the wind-chasing pirate
荒野を歩む
Walking through the wasteland
誇り高き騎士の頌歌（オード）
The ode of the proud knight
兎を追って落ちた穴には
In the hole fallen into while chasing a rabbit
世界の秘密 記されている
The world's secrets are recorded
過去も未来も幻だから
Because both past and future are illusions
いつでも君に会いにいけるよ
I can go to see you anytime
季節は巡りて
The seasons turn
友は先に老いゆき
Friends grow old before me
見守り、見送り
Watching over, seeing off
いつも残されて
Always being the one left behind
君の屍を森に還そう
Let's return your remains to the forest
いつか世界樹の下で会う
One day we'll meet under the World Tree
その時までは さよならだから
Until then, since it's goodbye
一粒の涙を
A single tear
時の水面に消えてゆく名を
The name fading on the surface of time
ただ一人だけ覚えていよう
Let me be the only one to remember it
ここには君が確かにいたと
That you were certainly here
古の調べは 生きた証を
The ancient melody, the proof you lived
明日も歌うだろう
Will likely sing tomorrow too
世界の果ての
At the edge of the world
大いなる樹を
To the great tree
讃えて歌おう
Let's sing in praise
アトリエ
Atelier
作詞・作曲:渡辺翔
Lyrics & Composition: Sho Watanabe
保険 言い訳 ばら撒いて
Scattering insurance and excuses
横切った未来振れ 途方に暮れないよう
So as not to be at a loss with the crossing future
未知数が憧れに
Even if the unknown variables
絡まったって奪えはしない
Get tangled with my yearnings, they can't be stolen
空を創ろう 散らかったパズル
Let's create the sky, even with scattered puzzles
組み合わせても 足りない
It's not enough even if combined
壁に写した 知らない世界の
Of the unknown world projected on the wall
前にあった 重い扉開け
Open the heavy door that was in front
忘れてた 少年の絵のように
Like the boy's painting I'd forgotten
温度は高く 微熱まじりで夢話していたい
I want to talk about dreams with a high temperature and a slight fever
もう憧憬は 描き飽きて
I'm tired of drawing yearnings already
全部を見るため 空いたアトリエ
An empty atelier to see everything
空いたアトリエ
Empty atelier
帰るアトリエ
Atelier to return to
いつかは
Someday...
想像して かきなぐって
Imagine, scribble it down
塗り替えても 外はもっと進んでいた
Even if I repaint it, the world outside was moving faster
不揃いな景色の中
Amidst the uneven scenery
棘が刺さっても 走ってみたい
I want to try running even if thorns prick me
道を創ろう 遠くなるほど
Let's create a path, as it gets further away
細く薄れて 描けない
It thins and fades, and I can't draw it
イメージをした 近い未来ぼやけたら
If the envisioned near future gets blurry
重い扉開け
Open the heavy door
その心 大胆に染めよう
Let's dye that heart boldly
いつかの絵さえ 霞むくらいの夢生み出したい
I want to create a dream that makes even that old painting pale
成果なんて わからない
I don't know about results or anything
きっとそれでも 去ったアトリエ
Surely even so, the atelier I left
去ったアトリエ
The atelier I left
僕の...
My...
僕のアトリエ
My atelier
いつでも
Always
どれだけ濡れても
No matter how wet it gets
擦ったって消えない
It won't disappear even if rubbed
戻せない
Can't go back
現実は鮮やか
Reality is vivid
忘れてた少年の絵のように
Like the forgotten drawing of a boy
温度は高く微熱まじりで
The temperature is high with a slight fever
夢話していたい
I want to keep talking about dreams
もう憧憬は描き飽きて
I'm already tired of drawing longing
全部を見るため
In order to see everything
空いたアトリエ
The empty atelier
帰るアトリエ
The atelier to return to
いつかは
Someday...
はい！ということで
Alright! With that...
聴いていただきました、2曲続けて聴いていただきましたが、楽曲の紹介させてください。
...you've just heard two songs in a row. Let me introduce them.
ユグドラシル、こちら未来古代楽団さんに作っていただきました。
'Yggdrasil' was created for me by Mirai Kodai Orchestra.
そしてアトリエ、こちらも渡辺翔さんに作っていただきました。
And 'Atelier' was created by Sho Watanabe.
私の大好きなアーティストさんに今回たくさん曲を作っていただけて...
I'm so happy that so many of my favorite artists created songs for me this time...
...いや本当に本当に幸せです。
...I'm truly, truly happy.
ま、ね、みんな察してるかと思うんですけど、今回のライブですね...
Well, I think everyone might have guessed, but for this live...
...全曲、オリジナル楽曲で組ませていただきました！
...the entire setlist is made up of original songs!
いや、本当に全てのアーティストさんに感謝。
I'm so grateful to all the artists.
そしてエルフレンドたちにも、本当に本当に感謝です。
And to all the Elfriends, thank you so much.
そしてゲストで来てくれた3期生もありがとう！
Also, thanks to the 3rd gen members who came as guests!
ま、次がですね、最後の曲になってしまうんですけど...
Well, the next one will be the last song...
...その前にですね、ちょっと、グッズの告知もね、ありますので、
...but before that, I have a merchandise announcement,
こちらですね、あの噂の、数量限定はあるのか、ないのか、
so please stay tuned until the very end...
ま、最後までですね、ちゃんと見ててくれると嬉しいなって思ってます。
...to see if the rumored limited edition items will be there!
ではですね、ちょっと最後の告知をしたいなって思い...あ、告知じゃない、
Now then, I'd like to do the final announcement... wait, not announcement,
最後の曲を、歌いたいなと思います。
I want to sing the last song.
この曲はですね、本当に色んな思い出があるんですけれども、
This song holds many different memories for me,
本当に、大大大好きなアーティストさん...
...by an artist I truly, truly, truly love...
...そして、それを締めくくるのはこちらのサブタイにもなっております、スカイソナー。
...and to wrap things up, here's 'Skysonar,' which is also the subtitle of this live.
この曲を書いてくださったのは...デン！奥井亜紀さんです！
The person who wrote this song is... Ta-da! It's Akiko Okui!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
こちらですね、コーラスまでみんなしっかりお聴き逃しなく！
Please don't miss any part of it, right down to the chorus!
では、歌わせていただきます、最後の曲。
Now, I'll sing my last song.
みんな今日来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you all for coming today!
スカイソナー / 作詞・作曲 奥井亜紀
Skysonar / Lyrics & Composition: Akiko Okui
四角い画用紙に大きな丸を描いたら
When you draw a big circle on a square piece of drawing paper
はしっこ少しずつ欠けてしまった思い散り散り
The edges gradually chippped away, and my thoughts scattered
大人になったらきっと綺麗に描けると
I thought that when I became an adult,
描けると思っていたんだ
I'd surely be able to draw it beautifully
人生100年なんて言うようになってらも
Even if they start saying life is 100 years long
子供でいられるのはたった20年なんだし
You can only be a child for 20 years
もっとゆっくり大人になってもいいんじゃない
Isn't it okay to become an adult more slowly?
自分にがっかりしないように
So as not to be disappointed in yourself
どこにもないものは誰もまだ知らないだけ
Things that are nowhere to be found are just things no one knows yet
形も名前も自由に掲げていいんだ
You can freely hold up any shape or name
もう一度描いてあなたの思うように
Draw it once more, just as you wish
青空みたいな画用紙広げて待ってる
I'm waiting with drawing paper spread out like the blue sky
夢より夢みたいな未来を
A future that's more like a dream than a dream
進め
Move forward
なんにもしないのはナニモデキナイカラッポで
Doing nothing means being empty and unable to do anything
助け...
Help...
助けてと言えない　みんなそれぞれ　大変なんだし
I can't say "help me" because everyone has their own struggles.
でも笑顔になれる　世界がすぐそばにあるじゃん！
But a world where you can smile is right there by your side!
気づいてワンクリック
Notice it with one click.
扉はひらく
The door opens.
優しい顔してる　幸せばかりじゃない
You have a kind face; it's not all about happiness.
険しい道にも　かわいい花が咲いている
Even on steep paths, cute flowers are blooming.
何度でも描いて　自惚れちゃう自画像
Draw it as many times as you like, a self-portrait you'll fall in love with.
青空みたいな画用紙　広げて待ってる
Drawing paper like a blue sky, I'm waiting with it spread out.
夢より夢みたいな未来で
In a future even more dreamlike than a dream,
会いたい
I want to see you.
かなしみは　よろこびに混ぜ合わせて
Mixing sadness together with joy,
くるしみは　しあわせに解け合いたい
I want suffering to melt away into happiness.
好きな色に生まれ変わるために
To be reborn in the colors I like.
どこにもないものは　誰もまだ知らないだけ
What can't be found anywhere is just something no one knows yet.
形も名前も　自由に掲げていいんだ
You can freely display its shape and name.
もう一度描いて　あなたの好きなように
Draw it once more, just the way you like.
青空みたいな画用紙　広げて待ってる
Drawing paper like a blue sky, I'm waiting with it spread out.
夢より夢みたいな未来を
A future even more dreamlike than a dream,
進め
Move forward.
みんな、今日のライブはどうだった？
Everyone, how was today's live?
不知火フレア活動３周年記念グッズのお知らせだよ。
Here's an announcement for Shiranui Flare's 3rd anniversary goods.
lack父さん描き下ろしのマガジンラックに、３周年にしてついに出しちゃう、エルフレンド証明書に、
A magazine rack illustrated by Lack-papa, and finally, for my 3rd anniversary, an Elfriend Certificate!
そして証明書も入れれちゃうおしゃれでかわいいIDカードケース。
And a stylish and cute ID card case that can even hold the certificate.
そしてグッズの最後はこいつはすごい！エルフレンドと私をイメージしたパーカーも出しちゃうぞ。
And the last item is amazing! A hoodie designed with the image of Elfriends and myself.
エルフレらしさだけじゃなくて、私らしさも入れちゃった。
I put not just Elfriend-style, but also my own style into it.
さらに気になる全部特典についてだよ。
Furthermore, here's information about the full set benefit.
３周年記念グッズをフルセットで購入してくれた方には特典で、
For those who purchase the full set of 3rd anniversary goods, as a bonus,
不知火フレア直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、lack先生描き下ろしポストカードが付いてくるよ。今回はなんと購入者全員に愛を込めて届けるから喧嘩しないでね。
you'll get a postcard illustrated by Lack-sensei, featuring my autograph and a foil-stamped message. This time, it'll be delivered to everyone who buys it with love, so please don't fight!
そしてそして！今日の全曲オリ曲ライブの中から一曲、
And also! One song from today's all-original-song live,
大好きなエルフレンドをテーマにした、「フレ・フレ・エルフレ」のMVをこの後22時10分からプレミア公開するよ。
the MV for "Fre-Fre-Elfriend", themed after my beloved Elfriends, will premiere at 22:10!
楽曲は0時からリリースされるからね。
The song will be released at midnight.
みんなに元気届けるからね。
I'll deliver energy to everyone.
私が3年頑張ってこれたのは、みんながいたからだよ。
The reason I've been able to work hard for three years is because you were all here.
いつもありがとう。
Thank you as always.
私から君への感謝の気持ち、ちゃんと届いてたら嬉しいな。
I hope my feelings of gratitude toward you reach you properly.
いつもありがとうだよ。
Thank you always.
大好きだぞ。
I love you all.
I love you.